Keller Mechanical Engineering Corporation Collection RG.001
Poly Archives & Special Collections at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
- Series III: Scrapbooks, 20th century; 1 letter-size manuscript box and 8 deep lid print boxes (14.5” x 18.5” x 3”)
  - Subseries B: Green Scrapbooks, 1931-1962
    - Photographs #5889 - #6749, 1959-1962 (Box 20)
- Series IV: Photographs, 1927-1962; 1 letter-size manuscript box and 1 print box (11.5" x 15" x 3")
  The sorted loose photographs were found in various boxes. They are arranged by photo number. Some photographs have descriptive information on the back, but most do not. For identification, consult the Record Book. Also included are loose advertisements featuring photographs found in the Record Book and ephemera related to the photographs, such as order slips with addresses. The "Additional Photographs," were grouped together with a cover sheet. Numbers on the cover sheet correspond to the Record Book.
  The unsorted photographs were so badly warped due to water damage that they could not be sorted into the collection. They are unavailable to researchers until treated by a conservator.
  The Detroit Kellering Company photo album contains a historical summary of the company on letter head. Photographs in the album are accompanied by captions, which identify buildings, people, machines, and products. Although the photographs are numbered, these numbers do not relate to the Record Book.
  - Subseries A: Photographs- Sorted, 1927-1962
    - Photographs #1145 - #2725, 1927-1936 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Photographs #3254 - #3255 with order slip, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Photographs #3573 - #4673, 1946-1954 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Photographs #4827 - #4991, 1954-1955 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Photographs #5075 - #5252, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Photographs #5309 - #5360, 1956-1957 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Photographs #5362 - #5858, 1957-1959 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Photographs #5874 - #5963, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Photographs #6005 - #6011, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Photographs #6314 - #6798, 1961-1962 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Photographs #6799 - #6802 (Many duplicates), 1962 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Photographs #6870 - #7534, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Un-numbered photographs, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Additional Photographs, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Subseries B: Photographs- Unsorted, undated (Box 22)
  - Subseries C: Detroit Kellering Company Photo Album, undated (Box 23)
- Series V: Publications, 1921-1935; letter-size manuscript box (Box 24)
  - Mechanical Engineering, 1921
    - "Dies Sinking and Metal Pattern-making by Automatic Machine", 1921 September; Keller, Joseph F. (Box 24, Folder 1, Object 1)
  - Automotive Industries, 1921
    - "A New Machine for Use in Sinking Large Dies", September 22, 1921 (Box 24, Folder 2, Object 1)
  - The Studebaker Co-Operator, 1925, 1925 August (Box 24, Folder 3, Object 1)
  - American Machinist, 1925
    - "Keller Toolroom Milling Machine, Type BL", 1925 September 17 (Box 24, Folder 4, Object 1)
  - Motor Vehicle Monthly, 1930
    - "Motor-Body Sheet-Steel Operations", 1930 April; Mercer, George J. (Box 24, Folder 5, Object 1)
  - Machinery, 1934
    - "The Dies Behind Those Streamlines", 1934 February (Box 24, Folder 6, Object 1)
  - The Iron Age, 1935
    - "Huge Keller Automatic Cuts Dies for New Large Auto Body Stampings", 1935 March 28 (Box 24, Folder 7, Object 1)
  - Machinery, 1935
    - "Unusual Jobs on Keller Machines", August, 1935; Herb, Charles Oliver, 1895- (Box 24, Folder 8, Object 1)
  - Backgrounds: A Pratt & Whitney Publication, Volume 1, 1940 (Object Bound volume)
- Series VI: Advertisements, 1916-1931
  - "American Machinist," 1916, 1916 December 7 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - "The American Drop Forger," 1918, 1918 June (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - "Forging-Stamping Heat Treating," 1926, 1926 October (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - "American Machinist," 1930 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - "Heat Treating and Forging," 1930 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - "Heat Treating and Forging," 1931 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - "American Machinist," 1931 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - "Machinery Trading Company," undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Series VII: Oversize, 1deep lid print box (14.5” x 18.5” x 3”)
  - Twenty-fifth anniversary certificate to Sidney A. Keller, 1921; This certificate was removed from a broken frame. The linen backing to the frame is also in the folder. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Photograph (13" x 18"), undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - The Hartford Times, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - The Hartford Courant, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Teapot sketch, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Series VIII: Product samples: Pratt & Whitney, Keller Department, undated; 1 deep lid print box (14.5” x 18.5” x 3”) (Box 26)
  One complete set of product samples from Pratt & Whitney, Keller Department are contained inside a painted wooden box with a leather handle. The sample dies are made from metal and stone. The loose samples were shipped to Marion Keller in 1985.
  - Metal template 2.5” x 4”, undated (Box 26, Object 1)
  - Sewing machine part 7” x 2 ¾”, undated (Box 26, Object 2)
  - Metal template 6” x 6”, undated (Box 26, Object 3)
  - Lincoln Kellering template, undated (Box 26, Object 4)
  - Alsace medallion, 1919 (Box 26, Object 5)
  - Reims Cathedral medallion, 1914 (Box 26, Object 6)
  - 3 piece template, undated (Box 26, Object 7)
  - Honeycomb airplane part, undated (Box 26, Object 8)
  - Watch fobs, undated (Box 26, Object 9)
  - Warren G. Harding fob, undated (Box 26, Object 10)
  - Traveling sales kit with product samples, Pratt & Whitney/KME, undated (Box 26, Object 11)
- Series IX: Covers: Notebooks and photo albums, undated; Many notebook and photo album covers were discarded due to mold infestation. Two of the three examples sustained mold damage and are encapsulated in plastic. The third did not sustain mold damage, but the photographs were removed from the album due to the damaging adhesive backing on the album pages. Use caution when observing these materials, especially those with mold allergies or respiratory issues.; 1 deep lid print box (14.5” x 18.5” x 3”) (Box 27)